Amrendra Kumar

AGM HRBP - Vodafone Idea Ltd

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Human Resource Leader passed out from XISS with 16+ years of experience in leading industries such as IT, Insurance and Telecom. Build and developed my competencies in designing and delivering business critical HR Solution and collaborate with HR Team and diverse business partner group in executing and delivering functional requirements. An accomplished HR Leader with clear understanding of HR practices including building pride in the organization, attracting, nurturing, developing & retaining talent. Motivated to learn, grow and excel professionally.

SKILLS

Thomas Certified Human Resource Professional with people management experience in a rapidly growing & changing environment.

<u>Areas of Expertise include:</u> ✓ Business Partnering ✓ Succession planning ✓ Talent Management ✓ HR Automation ✓ Employee Engagement ✓ Manpower Planning ✓ Talent Acquisition ✓ Performance Management ✓ Change Management (implementing Job Band across Circle) ✓ Team Building ✓ HR Policies & Procedures ✓ Employee Relations ✓ Skip Interview and ✓ Exit Interview.

√Highly enthusiastic, energetic with disciplined work habits. Developed leadership and team management skills. Self-driven and assertive with strong analytical and communication skills.

EDUCATION

- Executive Program in Human Resource Management from IIM-Calcutta (2017-18)
- ✓ Post-Graduation Diploma in Personnel Management from XISS, Ranchi(2003)
- ✓ Graduated from Ranchi University in B.Sc. (Honors- Chemistry)(2001)
- ✓ I.Sc. from Patna Science College, Patna(1997)
- ✓ ICSE from Bishop Westcott Boys' School, (1995)

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Vodafone Idea Ltd, Patna (Sep 2018 - Till Date) as AGM HRBP Ops Head Bihar & Jharkhand Circle:

Key Responsibilities:

- ✓ **Leading& Managing HR Agenda** Leading Complete Employee Life Cycle of Approx. 700employees including 390 regular, 220 Frontline sales and 90 associate employees across Bihar& Jharkhand Circle.
- ✓ **Business Partnering & Consulting** to providing guidance to managers on people initiatives such as career discussions, employee movement, performance management, managing difficult situations, managing marginal performers, managing span of control etc.
- ✓ Owned the **Talent Acquisition** and ensured that business has high quality and disruptive talent to support the growth agenda.
- ✓ Ensured smooth **On-boarding** by helping the new joiner familiarize themselves with the firm through the structured Induction and buddy program. Enhanced the new joiner connect with the team through continuous engagement.
- ✓ Played a pivotal role in transforming the **Performance Management** process through **Continuous Feedback Mechanism** and redefining the KRAs which lead to effective evaluation & feedback mechanism therefore increasing transparency in the system.
- ✓ Planned & successfully driven **Talent Management** initiatives in respective functions for succession planning & leadership development. Prepared **IDPs** (Individual Development Plans) for Top Talents identified through **Talent** Council.
- ✓ Designed & Implemented Circle **Rewards and Recognition** Scheme for employee leading to increase in employee satisfaction & morale across the region

- ✓ Successfully executed and implemented Action Plan of **Gallup Survey** for Leaders and Individual Mangers. Conducted **FGDs** based on Top 4 Priority areas as came in Survey result and helped in preparing action plan with regular reviews with Business Head along with Function Heads.
- ✓ Lead **Employee Engagement** initiative by conducting town-halls every month at Circle or during zone visits, conducted employee counseling & established employee connect.
- ✓ **Costing-**Preparing **Circle Manpower Budget** and cost and driving Manpower Planning and tracking the expense Vs approved budget month on month to save cost.
- ✓ Part of merger task force for **Vodafone Idea limited Deployment, Redundancy management** (VIL)

Idea Cellular Ltd, Patna (Nov 2012-Aug 2018) as AGM-HR Ops Head, Bihar & Jharkhand Circle:

- ✓ Lead employee engagement with structured action plan, Employee Segmented engagement, experience in compensation & benefit, Driving Performance Appraisal, Employee communication, Strategic Initiative, Operational Efficiency & Attrition management.
- ✓ Partnered with Business Leaders for implementation & adherence of HR strategy, policies and processes across Bihar & Jharkhand Circle.

Idea Cellular Ltd, Gujarat (June 2011-Oct 2012) as Manager-HR, VH Talent Acquisition-

- ✓ Spearheaded the **Talent Acquisition** process for Gujarat Circle with a team of one person. Managed end to end process of Internal Job Postings.
- ✓ Experienced in running **Assessment Centre** for internal job posting.
- ✓ Designed **HR Dashboard** which served as a performance monitoring tool for Talent Acquisition.

Max Newyork Life Insurance, Lucknow (May 2008-May 2011) as Regional Manager HR-

- ✓ Responsible for end to end employee life cycle including mass recruitment & controlling attrition with the focus on Talent Management through segmented engagement & driving operational efficiency.
- ✓ Got trained on Thomas Certification& competency based interview skills along with presentation skills.
- ✓ In 2008, when I joined the organization, I got opportunity to open new zonal offices thereby taking the zonal offices count from 13 to 30 nos with on-time recruitment of manpower & making the office operational in spread location of UP East.
- ✓ In 2010, I got the exposure of Change Management where I learnt the method of downsizing & how to handle employee issues and grievances while office got close down.

HCL Infosystem Ltd, Noida (Oct 2005 – May 2008) as Sr. Executive HR—Regional HR for North & East in computer division based at Corporate office. Responsible for Campus recruitment & driving employee engagement & Talent Management

Tarang Software Technology, Bangalore (Oct 2004-Sept 2005) as Executive – People Development –Responsible for recruitment through head hunting & Job Portal of IT Professionals. Sourcing of right profile for given vacancies, interviewed right candidate for the role & On-boarding of new hires.

PAT Incorporate, Bangalore (June 2003-Oct 2004) as Recruitment Specialist—Responsible for Client Interaction & providing relevant resumes to close the open positions.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- ✓ MDP creation for Talent Council employees based on competencies identified
- ✓ Awarded Idea Star Award in March 2014 for significant contribution in preparing HR Cost Budget 2014
- ✓ Awarded Idea Star Award in May 2016 for effectively managed Circle Bell Graph and drew insights and closure of PMS with CMT Members.
- ✓ Awarded Idea Star Award in Feb 2018 for significantly contributed to reposition the Talent Management process in Bihar Circle
- ✓ Recruited around 100 Candidates across MBA / Engineering / Diploma Institutes from different campuses across India which got recognized by HCLHR Head in record time of two months.
- ✓ Certification Program on Strategic Enablement for Business Result Simulation from en-Paradigm.

- ✓ Got certificate of accreditation as a PPA Practitioner from Thomas
- ✓ HR VAAD Training Program on Recruitment organized by ABG Group.

STRENGTH:

- ✓ Positive Attitude.
- ✓ **S**ensitive, **L**ogical & **C**ustomer Centric.
- ✓ Innovative & **O**riginal in approach.
- ✓ Good Team player & Empathetic
- ✓ Mobile and ready to accept challenges and deliver accordingly

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATEOFBIRTH: 25December1979

GENDER: Male

NATIONALITY: Indian

E-Mail: amrendra.techworld@gmail.com

Mobile: 9708097111/9508400335

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amrendrakumar1